Inside the Darlington Energy Complex in Clarington, Ontario
is one of the most significant training innovations
in the nuclear industry –
a state of the art facility
that replicates a Darlington reactor vault in full-scale
with every door, pipe,
hallway and light fixture the same as the real thing –
except here, there’s no radioactivity.
It’s the first full-scale version of its kind in the world
and it’s getting a lot of use.
So far, thousands of workers have experienced
unprecedented levels of realism in their training –
perfecting procedures and  techniques,
testing specialised tools
and becoming familiar with a nuclear environment.
All before they even set foot in the station.
It’s already making a difference,
the Darlington Refurbishment, Canada’s largest clean energy project,
is proceeding efficiently and safely
thanks to the innovation and training
developed here in Ontario.